[Music]
Hey Kyle, how are you doing? Bab, I'm
doing great. I'm just chuckling. You You
had a comment. There isn't anything that
I haven't done except for being the
founder of Keep Common and Refactor.
That I haven't done yet. So I
Yes, that's a good one. Um well um
really excited to have you uh Kyle. Um
now the floor is yours. Bab, thank you
so much. The Oh, I appreciate it. This
is going to be kind of a lightning talk
style because as I was presenting this
uh to my wife last night, she said,
"Kyle, you realize how far over time you
are." So I'm going to flip through very
very quickly. Um thank you Beth for the
kind introduction. I'm you know founder
of Runwen. We're building aic AI for
SRS, platform engineers, DevOps, etc.,
etc. But that you know this is a little
bit I pulled some numbers from our own
personal dev journey as a big users of
any and all AI engineering tools that we
can find for our own productivity. So I
kind of gonna start start
there I pulled this isn't very
scientific so my apologies if it's you
know if if that's kind of what you want.
This is a lot of back the envelope as I
look through our own uh history from a
bunch of repos. I just did kind of a
quarter-to- quarter comparison and some
monthly averages of before we were
using, you know, as many AI coding tools
as we possibly could. And after some of
this, I think the first stat on the left
is is old news for a lot of people who
are listening to this. We're up a solid
25% by lines of code written uh per
person uh after experimenting with a
whole bunch of different tools uh and
different people on the team settling
into a few. So that's pretty awesome. Um
the one in the middle as you know both
somebody who's contributed about half a
million lines of code for our product
and as the CEO the the middle one really
makes me very happy. We're up like 30%
of story points that we deliver in a
sprint and that's a big deal to me that
says I mean I'm watching it we get
through code much faster with you
less call like less mental energy spent
there. So a lot more mental energy gets
spent on are we doing the design
properly and are we really solving the
end user's problem before we even jump
into a new feature. So that that middle
one to me is really really interesting
and I don't think as many people uh in
the industry are talking about that. But
the right one is very interesting and I
hope a
little you know well let me just leave
it. It's interesting by lines of code
that we're actually running in
production, we're growing like 55%. Uh
growth per month of
55%. Because the sheer amount of using a
whole series of AI coding tools, the
amount of new open source that it's
bringing into our environment is
massive. Uh and kind of the our ability
to grow our tech stack is so fast. Um,
I'm sure that this will change over
time, right? As kind of as code bases
get very very very mature, the tech
stack changes a bit less. But this
is this is a fascinating stat and I'll
show you why in just a
sec. So here's another stat. We started
separating out we we compared like for
like PRs and we started calling them
landmines and we said hey when a
developer hits a landmine and we define
that as they hit a blocking issue
because it's somebody else's code is
doing something different from what they
expected in our shared environments. Uh
third party open source is doing
something different from what they
expected. Third party SAS is doing
something infrastructure. This was true
before we started using our AI coding
tools very heavily, but now it's
ridiculously visible. And I have to tell
you, like as the CEO of the company,
this is such a huge visible thing
because I just watch our our folks,
myself included, hey, here's a sprint
where you didn't hit a landmine and wow,
we're flying and here's a sprint where
you did. And hitting a landmine undoes
100% of the productivity benefit that
we've gotten from any AI tool ever.
I'm just going to if a developer hits a
landmine, all productivity gains are
lost. So, you know, look, this is like
this is a this for us is a is a problem
to
solve. I don't have as good stats on our
own uptime and downtime, but there's
kind of the S equivalent that we
certainly see amongst our customers um
in a big way. When a single S sur hits a
blocking issue that requires somebody
calling their colleagues, especially
when it requires multiple teams getting
involved, the MTR time jumps up by a
huge amount. Again, I don't have good
stats, but you know, we can kind of see
it and feel it. So, I'm assuming that if
we actually did, you know, pull some
customer stats here, you'd be able to
see it,
too. So, when we first start thinking
about like, hey, this is a problem that
we want to solve. There are two
interesting paths.
One was what if we took a technique that
a couple of us have seen at uh at fang
companies. It's been replicated by a
fairly small number of others and it's
almost like it's automation but think of
it almost like unit tests like let's
build a huge number of unit tests across
our infrastructure across all our third
party open source across our platform
etc and keep on building up from
there. It's a huge amount of work to get
it up and running. I mean, I saw this in
my on my last team. Uh, but once you do
have it up and running, it's
extraordinarily good signal to noise and
it's got this other really interesting
property uh that the human readable
text, hey, here's a here is a check and
the check failed and here's why. The
human readable text is
excellent. You know, hint about what's
going to happen next. The other path
that we didn't go down was, hey, let's
limit it to going back and forth with
observability tools. Look, it's much
less work up front. Um, but you're
missing a lot of context. And I think
anybody who started playing with this
area very seriously recognizes that your
metrics and logs alone require a lot of
other data to get fed into an LLM to get
anything useful back out. Um, it and a
lot of the most interesting thing that's
going on actually doesn't really have a
whole lot of human readable text. So
making this useful for LLMs, it's odd to
see that this troubleshooting data
that's useful for humans is actually
almost completely useless for LLMs. So
anyways, in very very very early on, we
made the design decision while we work
with observability tools to mostly focus
on building out these automated
checks. And our design goal kind of
evolved a couple of times over the
course of early development, but kind of
settled in like could we build something
like cursor.ai because we all love that
tool, but could we build it for S work?
not only for SRRES but for any developer
that is like at risk of hitting a
landmine. Hey my something is wrong. I
don't think it's my code. I think it's
something else. Can we avoid a landmine
really really really early by having a
cursor type of
thing? Check. Can you run 20 checks? Can
you run 30 checks? Can you explain to me
what's going
on? It's also used in production, right?
Obviously, like when an SR sees
something, oh my gosh, I'm seeing
something that I haven't seen before, or
I'm not really sure what this is, or I'm
not really sure even which team this is.
Um, same stuff applies in
prod. So, this was kind of the core
project that we
worked. What seemed like an interesting
like glimmer of an idea about two years
ago, it turns out that to make it work,
it needs lots and lots and lots of
tools.
We built up a library that's now got
like I don't know how many probably
seven or 8 hundred now. We add like 10 a
month. So it's it's a lot in the
library. And then when we do these
automated installs, you know, typically
we're talking about 5 to 10,000 tools
for a, you know, for a dev environment
because that's about the corpus of what
a really high-end expert human trying to
troubleshoot, you know, infrastructure
platform, oss, third party SAS, all the
way up into application logs and
metrics. That's kind of about the corpus
of skills that you expect in a in a real
expert engineer.
So it's fascinating because it's a lot
but it's not infinite. It's just a very
very very very large number of skills
called a very large number of tools.
Now I think since we're using you know
agentic AI at this tool
scale there's some really really really
interesting problems that are that are
emerging for us out on the other side. A
really hard problem became you can't
just dump it all into a context window
and hope for the best when you're trying
to do tool
selection. we have something we have to
solve something that looks an awful lot
more like
search to start selecting out from the
corpus like hey here's some interesting
tasks to run but it's a really
interesting search problem because you
know in typical search you have sort of
a couple of keywords in the query and
you have a couple of keywords in the
result and they kind of match here the
typical queries are describing a problem
like if you think about the body of an
alert or the body of like hey I think
this is down most of the words involved
describe the problem and they're not
actually those words actually don't show
up in the description of any of the
automated tools. So there's this really
interesting lexical translation problem.
There's also this really interesting
location problem that say I'm trying to
troubleshoot cart service. You know
using the you my old team sort of
canonical learn Kubernetes example of
online boutique. I'm trying to
troubleshoot cart service as a
deployment in Kubernetes but actually
the really interesting tasks are in the
online boutique namespace and I'd never
even mention the namespace as part of my
query.
So there's this very interesting
translation layer not only in terms of
problem to solution but there's this
really interesting translation layer in
between like where are you in the
infrastructure and and like what's
nearby you know which microservices are
you troubleshooting which are the
dependent ones okay which part of the
infrastructure are you in we used to
call it the New York versus London
problem or the dev versus prod problem
you really really really want to avoid
that high cost like terrible situations
where you're using you know this cursor
tool and suddenly you thought you were
troubleshooting something in dev
environment, it's like wandered off into
staging or even worse, wandered off into
prod. And we came up with what I think
is an interesting solution for that.
Very much inspired by Google Map search.
I mean, it's fascinating. You go into
Google Maps, you don't even think about
it. You type in like Thai food and then
you get all of these really interesting
search results where the word food was
not in the title because the web pages
say restaurant. Uh it's Thai and related
cuisines. And sometimes very often
nowhere on the web page does it actually
even say the word Thai which is I always
think is very interesting that they can
do that. Uh and second it winds up you
not searching for Thai restaurants all
over the entire planet but searching for
Thai restaurants that are really
relevant to my location. So long way of
saying you know we're on time in this
one but call the vector search that we
do is not traditional semantic search
only. It's semantic search as part of a
vector and then a lot of other
information in the vector that turns out
to make the search work really really
well. It's a very unique and interesting
search
domain and just find that area
fascinating. uh it's actually required
to make the agentic AI in the area go
well a fascinating nonpro that we
have because we sort of enumerate all of
these tools all these tasks uh all these
capabilities up front um our back
becomes really really
easy you know some people are allowed to
do remediation in dev environments but
not in production or some people are
allowed to do a lot of information
gathering in production but they have to
ask somebody else in the organization to
to help when it comes to times changing
config.
So that turned out to be a set of
extraordinarily easy problems to solve
that I think a lot of like AI for this
other 70% of engineering for these
troubleshooting problems
um has a really really really hard time
with and then if I look forward you know
an unsolved problem and I can tell you
with great certainty at least on our
side it's unsolved um like building MCP
servers with 10,000 plus tools
[Music]
is really really really straining I
think the intent of the MCP of of MCP
and and data A. So I think carving up
this problem space we're going to see a
lot of really really interesting best
practices emerge over the next one to
two years as MCP servers scale I mean
we're already there not only 10,000
tools but you know you add in you know
jer integration confluence integration
that kind of thing we our tool count
gets gets very very high in addition to
our own 10,000 and I think this is going
to be a fascinating area to watch we're
active in it and uh my guess is that I'm
sure that at least some of the other
presenters ers here starting to see
these early problems show up in their
own early product
design. That was my lightning talk as
fast as I could get it. I know that now
at this point, BAP, I think we were uh
back over to question to to Q&A and I
think that I I think that I think that
or at least I hope that I managed the
clock.
Hey K, thank you so much uh for uh this
very uh cool presentation and um yeah it
definitely seems like there is a huge
opportunity and I understand why yeah
you you are building uh this uh this
company um yeah just this concept of
landmines uh is definitely a very very
interesting one and how um yeah like
there's there's space to really improve.
Now I'm checking quickly and briefly uh
at uh the uh community and I think yeah
a lot of people were resonating uh with
uh what uh you were saying. Um just
quickly uh calling whether or not
anybody has uh any questions. Of course,
uh as I've mentioned in the past, like
um if any of you want to take this
aside, uh you can always directly
contact Kyle uh who I'm sure will be
very very happy to to have a chat on the
side. But uh I see Macy has an an
example. Uh Macy just commented. So
what's an example of a gnarly landmine?
That's a good one.
I mean I can tell you one that for not
one but two of our developers given like
the expectation of productivity that
we've now created for ourselves because
of all the tooling that we have um one
where we didn't have task coverage in
our own tool right so now like those are
like really really visible on our side
this happened about two about six weeks
ago or something like that
um it turns out we were using celery for
a series of kind of offline automation
um or offline kind of like longunning
task. We were using it as a job runner
um in one part of our infra and it was
the root cause was that Stellar was
effectively running out of memory. It
was clearly making a whole bunch of
calls that were appropriate in a small
dev environment and in our larger test
environments download gigantic gigantic
amounts of data.
um not super surprising, but the way
that it manifested itself like the fact
that it was actually these this sort of
off you know sort of offline job runner
manifest itself in these really weird
ways because it was shared test
infrastructure. We were running out of
Kubernetes cluster capacity. So a bunch
of other things were doing intermittent
failures and the failures were very
intermittent because this thing only on
some test runs would run selfway out of
memory. Um there were a series of
assumptions that we had in a very very
very early stage uh part of the code
about how long that those celery tasks
would take to run
uh and what happened if users were
taking several actions like while they
were still running which was just a
design error on our side and very very
early code but this really really
exposed it. We didn't see the celery
problem. We didn't see the memory
problem early on. We didn't all these
other problems manifest themselves.
So, it wound up
being two of our back-end folks, which
for us is kind of like sure, like
getting two people working on a problem
for like an hour. Okay, that's totally
normal, but there's two folks working on
this for like almost two and a half,
almost three full days because of the
really funky areas in our application
where this manifested itself.
um it was both an infrastructure
issue as well as an application issue
and it just happened to be in an area
that for our library we hadn't toolled
up. Um so I would say this was a gnarly
landmine because at this point for us
losing like two full days in a two week
sprint across two
people two years ago like it would have
been kind of an issue maybe but like
we're so much more productive now that
that's actually that's a huge loss.
H yeah. Ouch. As uh as Messi said
properly,
um yeah, I think that was a very very uh
insightful uh example. Um on our end, um
we think this is like probably the
perfect segue uh to jump into the the
next section. But before doing so, uh
just wanted to say uh a huge thank you
uh to you, Kyle. uh really really enjoy
uh this session. Uh one last little um
at the risk of uh making myself
redundant but um please reach out to
Kyle if you have any questions. Uh and
uh yeah, thank you so much for the
amazing chatter K. Thank you so much.
But I really appreciate the